Applied and Decorative Arts Slide Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Applied and Decorative Arts Slide Collection
1960-2005
VRC 1300
Yale University Arts Library
24
141 boxes in 24 containers
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of American and European applied and decorative arts, including arms and armor, book arts, calligraphy, ceramics, commercial design, enamels, furniture, gemanuscripts, glass, illuminated manuscripts, industrial design, intarsia, ivory, medals, metalwork, mosaics, musical instruments, numismatics, rugs, seals, stage design, tapestry, textiles, wallpaper and wood-carving.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of color and black and white 35 mm slides of American and European applied and decorative arts, including arms and armor, book arts, calligraphy, ceramics, commercial design, enamels, furniture, gemanuscripts, glass, illuminated manuscripts, industrial design, intarsia, ivory, medals, metalwork, mosaics, musical instruments, numismatics, rugs, seals, stage design, tapestry, textiles, wallpaper and wood-carving.
Arrangement
Arranged by medium. Principal sub-divisions by country, and where known, by individual artist name. Some sections preceded by materials arranged chronologically or by technique.
Decorative arts; Slides; Reproductions
- Arms and Armor (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous works [Slide box 1] (Box 1)
- Bookbinding (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
- Calligraphy (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
- Ceramics (Transfer to Babylonian Collection, 2008)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
  - Egypt (Box 1)
  - Near East
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
    - Persia (Box 1)
  - Aegean (Box 1)
  - Greece
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
    - Proto-Geometric (Box 1)
    - Geometric (Box 1)
    - Orientalizing (Box 1)
    - Corinthian (Box 1)
    - Black Figure (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
      - Nessos Vase (Box 1)
      - Exekias (Box 1)
    - Dimorphic or Bilingual (Box 1)
    - Red Figure
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
      - Achilles Painter (Box 1)
      - Andokides Painter (Box 1)
      - Berlin Painter (Box 1)
      - Brygos Painter (Box 1)
      - Copenhagen Painter (Box 1)
      - Dinos Painter (Box 1)
      - Douris Painter (Box 1)
      - Euphronios Painter (Box 1)
      - Eretria Painter (Box 1)
      - Kleophon Painter (Box 1)
      - Kleophrades Painter (Box 1)
      - Makron (Box 1)
      - Niobid Painter (Box 1)
      - Onesimos Painter (Box 1)
      - Pan Painter (Box 1)
      - Peithinos (Box 1)
      - Peithesilea Painter (Box 1)
      - Persephone Painter (Box 1)
      - Phintias (Box 1)
      - Poygnotus (Box 1)
      - Pronomos Painter (Box 1)
      - Tripolemos Painter (Box 1)
    - White Ground
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
      - Achilles Painter (Box 1)
    - Hellenistic (Box 1)
    - South Italian (Box 1)
  - Etruscan
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
    - Bucchero Vase (Box 1)
  - Roman (Box 1)
  - Coptic (Box 1)
  - Early Medieval (Byzantine) [SLide box 2] (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
  - Austria (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
  - Britain (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
    - Earthenware (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
      - Slipware (Box 1)
      - Creamware (Box 1)
      - Lead-Glaze (Box 1)
      - Tin-Glaze (Box 1)
      - Delftware [Slide boxes 2-3] (Box 1)
    - Stoneware [Slide box 3] (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
      - Salt-Glaze (Box 1)
    - Porcelain (Box 1)
    - Staffordshire (Box 1)
    - Wedgwood [Slide box 4] (Box 1)
    - Known Artists (Box 1)
      - Various Artists (Box 1)
      - De Morgan, William (Box 1)
      - Dresser, Christopher (Box 1)
      - Morris, William (Box 1)
    - 20th century (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - France (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous Artists (Box 1)
    - Gauguin, Paul, 1848-1903 (Box 1)
    - Palissy, Bernard, 1510-1589 (Box 1)
  - Germany [Slide boxes 4-5] (Box 1)
  - Greece [Slide box 5] (Box 1)
  - Holland (Box 1)
  - Italy (Box 1)
  - Russia (Box 1)
  - Spain (Box 1)
  - Switzerland (Box 1)
  - United States (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
    - Earthenware (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous works [Slide boxes 5-6] (Box 1)
      - Queensware [Slide box 5] (Box 1)
      - Redware (Box 1)
      - Slipware (Box 1)
    - Stoneware (Box 1)
    - Porcelain (Box 1)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 1)
      - William E. Tucker/Hampill & Co. (Box 1)
      - Chinese export porcelain (all dates) (Box 1)
      - White House Porcelain China (all dates) [Slide box 7] (Box 2)
    - 20th century (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
      - Briggle, Artus Van (Box 2)
      - Cowan Pottery Studio (Box 2)
      - Grotell, Maija (Box 2)
      - Hall China (Box 2)
      - Heat, Edith (Box 2)
      - Higby, Wayne, 1943- (Box 2)
      - Lenox, Inc. (Box 2)
      - Marks, Graham, 1951- (Box 2)
      - Nagle, Ron, 1939- (Box 2)
      - Poor, Henry Varnun, 1888-1971 (Box 2)
      - Robineau, Adelaide Alsop, 1865-1929 (Box 2)
      - Roodwood Pottery (Box 2)
      - Rothman, Jerry (Box 2)
      - Saxe, Adrian, 1943 (Box 2)
      - Schneckengost, Victor (Box 2)
      - Soldner, Paul [Slide box 8] (Box 2)
      - Vnock, Irene, 1952- (Box 2)
      - Voulkos, Peter, 1924- (Box 2)
      - Wright, Russell, 1904- (Box 2)
- Commercial Design (Box 2)
  - Advertisement (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
    - Life [Slide box 9] (Box 2)
    - Saturday Evening Post (Box 2)
    - Vogue (Box 2)
    - Auto Ads (Box 2)
    - Movie Ads (Box 2)
  - Book Jackets (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Books (text pages) (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Brochures [Slide box 10] (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Catalogues (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Department Store Display (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Display Windows (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Magazine Covers (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
    - Saturday Evening Post Covers (Box 2)
  - Postcards [Slide box 11] (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Posters (Box 2)
    General
    Xx Prints any country and Artist
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Britain (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - France (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Germany (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Italy (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Switzerland (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Unites States (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works [Slide boxes 11-12] (Box 2)
    - Record Albums [Slide box 12] (Box 2)
    - Signs and Street signs (Box 2)
    - Artists (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous artists (Box 2)
      - Leyendecker, J.C., 1874-1961 (Box 2)
- Enamel (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 2)
  - Britain [Slide box 13] (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - Flanders (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - France (Box 3)
    - 12th Century (Box 3)
    - 13th Century (Box 3)
    - 16th Century (Box 3)
  - Germany (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - Italy (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
    - Ugolino di Vieri (Box 3)
      Xx Metal Italy 14th century
- Furniture (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - Egypt (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - Medieval (Box 3)
    Xx S. Peters Chair, see also sculpture Italy, Bernini
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - Austria (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
    - Hoffman, Josef, 1870-1986 (Box 3)
    - Moser, Kolo, 1868-1918 (Box 3)
    - Peche, Dagobert, 1887-1923 [Slide box 15] (Box 3)
    - Wagner, Otto, 1841-1918 (Box 3)
  - Belgium (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - Britain (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
    - Windsor (Box 3)
    - 16th Century (Box 3)
    - Early 17th Century (Box 3)
    - Late 17th Century (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
      - Chairs (Box 3)
      - Queen Anne (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
        - Chairs (Box 3)
      - George II [Slide box 16] (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
      - Chippendale (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
        - Chairs (Box 3)
    - Early Classic Revival (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
      - Adam, Robert (Box 3)
        Xx Architecture Renaissance Britain under specific houses and under General Architects
    - Empire (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
    - Victorian (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
      - Known Artists (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous artists (Box 3)
        - Godwin, Edward William, 1833-1886 [Slide box 17] (Box 3)
        - Morris, William, 1834-1896 (Box 3)
        - Pugin, Augustus Welby, 1812-1852 (Box 3)
        - Rossetti, D.G., 1828-1882 (Box 3)
        - Webb, Philip, 1831-1915 (Box 3)
      - 20th Century (Box 3)
        - Miscellaneous Artists (Box 3)
        - Gray, Eileen, 1878-1976 (Box 3)
        - Lutyens, Ewin L., 1869-1944 (Box 3)
        - Mackinstoh, Charles Rennie, 1868-1928 (Box 3)
        - Voysey, C.F.A. 1857-1941 (Box 3)
  - Finland [Slide box 18] (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
  - France (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
    - 17th Century (Box 3)
    - 18th Century (Box 3)
    - 19th Century (Box 3)
    - 20th Century (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 3)
      - Chareau, Pierre, 1883-1950 (Box 3)
      - Le Cobusier, 1887-1965 (Box 3)
      - Legrain, Pierre, 1889-1929 (Box 3)
      - Mallet-Stevens, Robert, 1886-1945 (Box 3)
      - Perriand, Charlotte, 1903- (Box 3)
        Xx Architecture 19th–20th century, France- General
      - Ruhlmann, Jacques Emile, 1879-1933 [Slide box 19] (Box 4)
      - Sognot, Louis, 1892-1970 (Box 4)
  - Germany (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - 19th Century (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - 20th Century (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
      - Behrens, Peter, 1868-1940 (Box 4)
      - Breuer, Marcel (Box 4)
        Xx Furniture U.S.
      - Gropius, Walter, 1883-1969 (Box 4)
      - Mies van der Rohe, 1886-1969 (Box 4)
      - Olbrich, Joseph, 1876-1908 (Box 4)
  - Greece (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
  - Holland (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Rietveld, Gerrit, 1888-1964 (Box 4)
  - India (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
  - Italy (Box 4)
    - 14th Century (Box 4)
    - 15th Century (Box 4)
    - 16th Century (Box 4)
    - 17th Century [Slide box 20] (Box 4)
    - 18th Century (Box 4)
    - 20th Century (Box 4)
  - Norway (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
  - Portugal (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
  - Spain (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Gaudi, Antonio, 1852-1926 (Box 4)
  - Latin America (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
  - United States (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Folk styles (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Ladderback (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Pennsylvania German (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Shaker [Slide box 21] (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Spanish Colonial (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
    - Windsor (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
      - New Haven (Box 4)
      - Winterthur (Box 4)
    - 17th Century (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
      - Boxes [Slide box 22] (Box 4)
      - Chairs (Box 4)
      - Chests (Box 4)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
        - New Haven (Box 4)
        - Winterthur (Box 4)
      - Cupboard (Box 4)
      - Tables [Slide box 23] (Box 4)
      - Known Artists (Box 4)
    - 18th Century (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
      - William and Mary (Box 4)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 4)
        - Chairs [Slide boxes 23-24] (Box 4)
        - Miscellaneous works [Slide box 24] (Box 4)
        - New Haven (Box 4)
        - Winterthur (Box 4)
        - Chests (Box 4)
        - Desk & Bookcase (secretary) (Box 4)
        - High Chest (High Boys) (Box 4)
        - Dressing Table (Low Boys) [Slide box 24-25] (Box 4–5)
        - Tables [Slide box 25] (Box 5)
        - Known Artists (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
          - Clement Samuel (Box 5)
      - Queen Anne (Box 5)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
        - Chairs (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
          - New Haven (Box 5)
          - Winterthur [Slide boxes 25-26] (Box 5)
        - Chests on Chest [Slide box 26] (Box 5)
        - High Chest (High Boys) (Box 5)
        - Tables (Box 5)
        - Known Artists (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
            - Pimm, John (Box 5)
      - Chippendale (Box 5)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
        - Chairs [Slide box 27] (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
          - New Haven (Box 5)
          - Winterthur [Slide boxes 27-28] (Box 5)
        - Chests [Slide box 28] (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
          - New Haven (Box 5)
          - Winterthur (Box 5)
        - Clocks (Box 5)
        - Desks (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
          - New Haven (Box 5)
        - High Chest [Slide boxes 28-29] (Box 5)
        - Dressing Tables [Slide box 29] (Box 5)
        - Mirrors (Box 5)
        - Tables (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
          - New Haven (Box 5)
          - Winterthur (Box 5)
        - Known artists (Box 5)
          - Miscellaneous artists (Box 5)
          - Chapin, Eliphalet (Box 5)
          - Randolph, Benjamin [Slide box 30] (Box 5)
          - Ritterihouse, David, 1767-1771 (Box 5)
          - Savery, William (Box 5)
          - Townsend, John (Box 5)
          - Tuffts, Thomas (Box 5)
    - 19th Century (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
    - Federal (Early Classic Revival) (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
      - Chairs (Box 5)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 5)
        - New Haven (Box 5)
        - Winterthur [Slide boxes 30-31] (Box 5–6)
      - Chest (Chest on Chest) [Slide box 31] (Box 6)
      - Desk (Desk on Bookcase secretary) (Box 6)
      - Mirror (Box 6)
      - Sideboards (Box 6)
      - Sofas (Box 6)
      - Tables (Box 6)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
        - New Haven [Slide box 32] (Box 6)
      - Known Artists (Box 6)
        - Miscellaneous Artists (Box 6)
        - Adams, Nehemiah (Box 6)
        - Allison, Michael (Box 6)
        - Banks, John (Box 6)
        - Badlam, Stephen, and Skillin, Simeon (Box 6)
        - Barry, joseph & Son (Box 6)
        - Braumers, Joseph [Slide box 33] (Box 6)
        - Findlay (Box 6)
        - Frederick, Charles & Harrington, Benjamin (Box 6)
        - Hainnes, Connolly Son (Box 6)
        - Haskell, William (Box 6)
        - Johnson, Edmond (Box 6)
        - Kneeland & Adams (Box 6)
        - Lannvier, C.H. (Box 6)
        - Lemon, William (Box 6)
        - McIntire, Samuel, 1757-1811 (Box 6)
        - Mills & Deming (Box 6)
        - Phyfe, Duncan (Box 6)
        - Seymour, John and Thomas (Box 6)
        - Rawson, Joseph & Son (Box 6)
        - Ruggles, Levi (Box 6)
        - Sanderson, Jacob (Box 6)
        - Seymour, john (Box 6)
        - Short, Joseph (Box 6)
        - Toppan, Agner (Box 6)
      - Empire (Late Classic Revival) (Box 6)
        - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
        - Chairs (Box 6)
          - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
          - New Haven (Box 6)
        - Desk (Desk & Bookcase) (Box 6)
        - Sofas (Box 6)
        - Tables (Box 6)
    - Victorian (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
      - Interiors [Slide box 34] (Box 6)
      - Known Artists (Box 6)
        Xx for 1860 Rocking Chair formerly attributed to Peter Cooper (New York, Cooper Union), see Furniture Britain Victorian
        - Miscellaneous Artists (Box 6)
        - Belter, John Henry, 1804-1863 (Box 6)
        - Brooks, Thomas and Son (Box 6)
        - Davis, A.J. (Box 6)
        - Herter (Box 6)
        - Richardson, H.H. (Box 6)
        - Roux, Alexander, 1813-1886 (Box 6)
        - Whistler, J.A.M., 1834-1903 (Box 6)
    - 20th Century (Box 6)
      - Known artists (Box 6)
        - Albers, Josef (Box 6)
        - Bertoia, Harry, 1915- (Box 6)
        - Breuer, Marcel Lajos, 1902-1961 [Slide boxes 34-35] (Box 6)
        - Castel, Wendell [Slide box 35] (Box 6)
        - Deskey, Donald, 1894-1989 (Box 6)
        - Eames, Charles, 1901- (Box 6)
          Xx Photography U.S. 20th c. "Stroboscopic", for a man in Eames chair showing movement 93x4 Lantern slides)
        - Esherick, Wharton, 1887-1970 (Box 6)
        - Frankl, Paul T., 1887-1958 (Box 6)
        - Gehry, Frank, 1929- (Box 6)
        - Graves, Michael, 1934- (Box 6)
        - Greene, Charles & Henry (Box 6)
        - Knoll, Florence (Box 6)
        - Moser, Thomas (Box 6)
        - Nakashima, George, 1905- (Box 6)
        - Nelson, George (Box 6)
        - Nessen, Walter von, 1889-1943 (Box 6)
        - Richardson, H. H. (Box 6)
        - Rohde, Gilbert, 1894-1944 (Box 6)
        - Rorimer, Louis, 1872-1939 (Box 6)
        - Saarinen, Eero, 1910- (Box 6)
        - Schoen, Eugene, 1880-1957 (Box 6)
        - Speaker, Michael (Box 6)
        - Venturi, Robert, 1925- (Box 6)
        - Weber, Kem, 1889-1963 [Slide box 36] (Box 6)
        - Wormley, Edward (Box 6)
        - Wright, Frank Lloyd (Box 6)
        - Wright, Russel, 1904- (Box 6)
- Gems (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
  - Roman (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
    - Gemma Agustea (Box 6)
  - Early Medieval or Byzantine (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
- Glass (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
  - Egypt (Box 6)
  - Near East (Box 6)
  - Roman (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous works (Box 6)
    - Portland Vase (Box 6)
  - Early Medieval (Box 6)
  - Austria (Box 6)
  - Britain (Box 6)
  - Czechoslovakia (Box 6)
  - Denmark (Box 6)
  - Finland (Box 6)
  - France (Box 6)
  - Germany (Box 6)
  - Holland (Box 6)
  - Italy (Box 6)
  - Unites States (Box 7)
    - 18th Century [Slide box 37] (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 7)
      - Manheim, PA (Box 7)
      - Amelung J. Frederic (Box 7)
    - 19th Century (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 7)
    - 20th Century (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous works (Box 7)
      - Sandwich (Box 7)
      - Steuben (Box 7)
      - Tiffany (Box 7)
- Illuminations (Manuscripts) (Box 7)
  - Greek and Roman [Slide box 38] (Box 7)
    - Ambrosian Calendar (Box 7)
    - Notita Dignitatum (Box 7)
    - Vergilius Romanus (Box 7)
    - Virgilius Vaticanus (Box 7)
  - Dura-Europos (Box 7)
  - Coptic (Box 7)
  - Early Christian and Byzantine (Box 7)
    - 4th century (Box 7)
    - 5th century (Box 7)
      - Cotton Genesis (Box 7)
    - 6th century (Box 7)
      - Vienna Dioscurides (Box 7)
      - Rabbula Gospels (Box 7)
      - Bassano Gospels (Box 7)
      - Sinope Gospels (Box 7)
      - Vienna Genesis [Slide boxes 38-39] (Box 7)
    - 7th century [Slide box 39] (Box 7)
      - Ashburnham Pentateuch (Box 7)
    - 8th century (Box 7)
      - Syriac Gospels (Box 7)
    - 9th century (Box 7)
      - Book of Job (Vatican Grec.749) (Box 7)
      - Gregory of Nazianzus (Paris, Gr.510) (Box 7)
      - Khludov Psalter [Slide boxes 39-40] (Box 7)
    - 10th century [Slide box 40] (Box 7)
      - Joshua Roll (Box 7)
      - Bible of Leo the Patrician (Vatican) (Box 7)
      - Paris Psalter (Box 7)
      - Stauronikita Gosepel (Box 7)
    - 11th century (Box 7)
      - Various [Slide boxes 40-41] (Box 7)
      - Cynegetica (Venice, Bib.Marciana) [Slide box 41] (Box 7)
      - Gospel Book (Paris, Bib.Nat. Grec.64) (Box 7)
      - Gospel Book (Paris, Bib.Nat. Grec.74) (Box 7)
      - Gospel Lectionary (Mt.Athos, Dionysiou) (Box 7)
      - Gregory of Nazianzus (Paris,Bib.Nat. Grec.533) (Box 7)
      - Homilies, S.John Chrysostom (Paris,Bib.Nat. Coislin 79) (Box 7)
      - Menologion of Basil II (Vatican, Grec. 1613) (Box 7)
      - Menologion for January (Baltimore, Walters 521) (Box 7)
      - Psalter, c.1059 (Vatican, Grec.752) (Box 7)
      - Psalter of Basil II (Venice, Marciana) (Box 7)
      - Psalter and New Testament (Dumbarton Oaks manuscripts3) (Box 7)
      - Theriaca of Nicander (Paris, Bib.Nat.Grec. 247) (Box 7)
      - Theodore Psalter (London, BM Add. 19352) (Box 7)
    - 12th century (Box 7)
      - Various [Slide boxes 41-42] (Box 7)
      - Gospel Book (Mt. Athos, S.Panteleimon, Cod.25) [Slide box 42] (Box 7)
      - Gregory of Nazianzus, Homilies (Mt.Sinai, S.Catherine, Gr.339) (Box 7)
      - Gregory of Nazianzus, Sermons (Paris, Grec. 943 and 550) (Box 7)
      - Homilies of Monk James (Vatican, Grec. 1162) (Box 7)
      - Octateuch (Topkapi, manuscripts6) (Box 7)
      - Panoplia dogmatica (Vatican Grec.666) (Box 7)
      - Skylitzes Chronicle (Madrid) (Box 7)
    - 13th century (Box 7)
      - Various (Box 7)
      - Gospel Book (Mt. Athos, Iveron, manuscripts5) (Box 7)
      - Gospel Lectionary (Mt.Athos, Koutloumousiou manuscripts61) (Box 7)
      - Lectionary, Syriac, c.1250 (Deir es-Zafaran) (Box 7)
      - Palatine Psalter (Vatican, Pal.Grec.381) (Box 7)
    - 14th century [Slide box 43] (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Crusader Manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Various (Box 8)
    - Arsenal Bible (Paris) (Box 8)
    - Bible, Old Testament (Paris, Bib.Nat. nouv.acq. fr..1404) (Box 8)
    - Histoire d'Outremer (various manuscripts) (Box 8)
    - Histoire Universelle (various manuscripts) (Box 8)
    - Queen Melisende's Psalter (London, BM) (Box 8)
  - Celtic [Slide box 44] (Box 8)
    - Variou (Box 8)
    - Bede (various manuscripts) (Box 8)
    - Canterbury Psalter (London, BM) (Box 8)
    - Codex Amiatinus (Florence, Laurentian) (Box 8)
    - Codex Aureus (Stockholm, manuscriptsA.135) (Box 8)
    - Cutbercht Gospels (Vienna manuscripts1224) (Box 8)
    - Durham Cassiodorus (Box 8)
    - Durham Gospel Fragments (Box 8)
    - Book of Dimma (Box 8)
    - Book of Durrow (Box 8)
    - Echternach Gospels (Box 8)
    - Book of Kells (Box 8)
      - Canon Table (Box 8)
      - Symbols of Evangelists (Box 8)
      - Gospels (Box 8)
        - Gospel of Matthew (Box 8)
        - Gospel of Mark (Box 8)
        - Gospel of Luke [Slide boxes 44-45] (Box 8)
        - Gospel of John [Slide box 45] (Box 8)
    - Lindisfarne Gospels (Box 8)
    - Irish Gospel Book of S. Gall (Box 8)
    - Macregol Gospels (Box 8)
    - Maeseyck Gospels (Box 8)
    - S.Chad Gospels [Slide boxes 45-46] (Box 8)
    - S. Columcille Cathach (Dublin, Royal Acad.) [Slide box 46] (Box 8)
    - Trier Gospels (Box 8)
  - Merovingian (Box 8)
    - Various (Box 8)
    - Corbie Psalter (Box 8)
    - Gelasian Sacramentary (Vatican) (Box 8)
    - Gellone Sacramentary (Box 8)
    - Gospel Book of Gudohinus (Autun) (Box 8)
    - Luxueil Lectionary (Paris, Bib.Nat.Lat.9427) (Box 8)
    - S.Augustine, Questions on the Heptateuch (Paris, Bib.Nat.Lat.12168) (Box 8)
  - Carolingian (Box 8)
    - Various (Box 8)
    - Apocalypse of Cambrai (Cambrai manuscripts386) (Box 8)
    - Egmo Codex, Verons (Berlin, manuscriptsphill.1676) (Box 8)
    - Evangelary c.800 (Essen) (Box 8)
    - Gospel Book, 9th c (Baltimore,Walters, manuscripts4) (Box 8)
    - Paris Terence (Box 8)
    - Psalter of Mondsee (Montpellier manuscripts 409) (Box 8)
    - Quedlinberg Evangelary (Box 8)
    - Vatican Terence (Box 8)
    - Charlemagne Court School (Box 8)
      - Ada Gospels [Slide boxes 46-47] (Box 8)
      - Godescalc Gospels [Slide box 47] (Box 8)
      - Harley Gospels (Box 8)
      - Lorsch Gospels (Box 8)
      - S.Medard of Soissons Gospel (Box 8)
    - Coronation Group (Box 8)
      - Gospels of Charlemagne (Box 8)
    - Reims School (Box 8)
      - Various (Box 8)
      - Aratos, Phainomena (Leiden Univ.Lib.Voss Lat.Q79) (Box 8)
      - Ebbo Gospels (Box 8)
      - Gospel Book (Morgan M.640) (Box 8)
      - Gospel Book (Morgan M.720) (Box 8)